### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/patrickjensen (LinkedIn)

www.metavisuals.com (Other) www.skybrushstudios.com (Other) www.artstation.com/patrickjensen (Other)

### Top Skills

Digital Painting
Photoshop
Art Direction

### **Publications**

d'artiste Matte Painting
The Art of the Book of Life
Grand Space Opera (CG Challenge)
Advanced Photoshop (Issue 56)
ImagineFX

# Patrick Jensen

Art Director at Meta - Horizon

San Mateo, California, United States

## Summary

Email: patrick@metavisuals.com

Portfolio: www.metavisuals.com

Artstation: www.artstation.com/patrickjensen

Patrick is an Art Director with 18+ years of experience in Film, Animation, VFX, Gaming and VR in both support and leadership roles. A positive, proactive, and versatile collaborator, with a pure desire to entertain audiences and craft memorable experiences with great people.

## Experience

#### Meta

Art Director at Meta - Horizon January 2020 - Present (3 years 4 months) Menlo Park, CA

#### **METAVISUALS**

Freelance Art Direction / Concept Design / Illustration Services June 2013 - Present (9 years 11 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

www.metavisuals.com

METAVISUALS houses the personal creative services of Patrick Jensen, which include Art Direction, Concept Design, and Illustration for the Film / TV / Game / XR industries.

Selection of Clients Include:

Ascendant Studios, Amazon Studios, Nimble Collective, Atomic Fiction, Oculus Story Studio, Reel FX, Wizards of the Coast, Pullstring Inc., Telltale Games

Skybrush Studios Inc.
Founder | Chief Creative Officer
July 2018 - Present (4 years 10 months)

Page 1 of 4

#### San Francisco Bay Area

Founded Skybrush Studios Inc. to craft lush, cinematic, and heartfelt adventures for PC & Console.

Telltale Games
Senior Concept Artist / Matte Supervisor
October 2016 - September 2018 (2 years)
San Rafael, CA

**Unannounced Projects** 

The Walking Dead: Season 3 and 4

Guardians of the Galaxy: The Telltale Series

Batman: The Telltale Series
Minecraft: Story Mode Season 2

PullString, Inc.
Senior Technical / Visual Development Artist
March 2016 - July 2016 (5 months)

Telltale Games Lead Concept Artist & Storyboards June 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 10 months) San Rafael, CA

Game of Thrones - A Telltale Games Series
Tales from the Borderlands
The Walking Dead: Michonne

- Helped mentor a team of environment artists, character and environment concept artists through hands on training, painting demos, and informal critiques.
- Helped art direct visual development exploration, line-work, callouts, lighting keys and matte paintings, both internally and the work coming in from outsourcers - specifically on achieving the style of brushwork, color variety, and lighting that was needed for Telltale's Game of Thrones.
- Built a more streamlined concept pipeline that aided both the aggressive production schedule as well as the overlap between concept artists and the environment artists.
- Created a matte painting pipeline for all projects at Telltale that aided skydomes, allowed for set extensions and helped ease the workload of the effects department.

Sony Computer Entertainment America

Senior Artist

February 2014 - March 2014 (2 months)

For the debut of Project Morpheus - PlayStation's prototype virtual reality system for PS4

- Designed and animated the dragon to end the "Castle Demo", shown at GDC 2014.
- Worked with Research & Development team to create props, sets, and characters for various tech demos.

DreamWorks Animation

Matte Painter

September 2013 - January 2014 (5 months)

Mr. Peabody & Sherman

Reel FX

Visual Development Artist September 2013 - September 2013 (1 month)

Book of Life

Wizards of the Coast Concept Designer June 2013 - July 2013 (2 months)

**Dungeons & Dragons** 

Lucasfilm Animation
Senior Lighting Concept Designer
October 2010 - May 2013 (2 years 8 months)
San Rafael, CA

Star Wars: Detours

- Oversaw development and execution of lighting by painting lighting keys and giving clear Art Direction and paintovers to local artists and studios overseas
- Created show-wide style guides to foster visual objectives for designers and artists
- Instructed teams on Maya/Photoshop techniques, matte painting workflows, and pipeline recommendations to increase overall quality and efficiency
- Mentored artists through hands on training and development of career objectives

- Created cartoony and stylized environment, character, and vehicle concept art
- Filled in for CG Supervisor or Art Lead during asset review meetings, lighting dailies, design rounds, when they are unavailable or if extra support is needed

DreamWorks Animation Visual Development Artist / Matte Painter May 2005 - October 2010 (5 years 6 months) Redwood City, CA

Megamind Shrek, Forever After Shrek, The Third Monsters vs. Aliens Over The Hedge

Shrek The Halls (TV)

Monsters vs. Aliens - Mutant Pumpkins from Outer Space (TV)

The Madagascar Penguins in a Christmas Caper (TV)

Merry Madagascar (TV)

Pixar Animation Studios Lighting TD Intern May 2004 - August 2004 (4 months) Emeryville, CA

• Worked closely with Sharon Calahan (Director of Photography) to learn Pixar's approach to lighting and rendering for 'Ratatouille' while testing new internal lighting tools

### Education

Ringling College of Art and Design BFA, Computer Animation (2001 - 2005)

Hong Kong International School (1997 - 2000)